<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
   	<title>panke.me - Tag: realjenius.com</title>
   
   <link>http://panke.me</link>
   <description>I'm a software developer in the game industry, and have been (for better or worse) coding on the Java platform for the last decade. I also do all my own stunts.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>panke</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
  <title>Media Temple Makes a Deal with the Devil</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2013/10/15/a-deal-with-the-devil.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2013-10-15T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2013/10/15/a-deal-with-the-devil.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>Today, Media Temple announced that they are being acquired by GoDaddy.</p>

<p>Here’s a tip for Media Temple: if you have to spend your entire FAQ trying to convince folks that the acquisition isn’t a bad idea… maybe <strong>it actually is a bad idea.</strong></p>

<p>But surely, that’s not enough reason to switch hosts. It seems silly to move, just because of an acquisition that Media Temple has said so strongly <a href="http://weblog.mediatemple.net/2013/10/15/faqs-about-the-godaddy-acquisition/">won’t affect their service</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
  <h4 id="what-about-godaddys-reputation-in-the-tech-community">What about GoDaddy’s reputation in the tech community?</h4>
  <p>GoDaddy has been transformed in recent months and is essentially a new company. If we did not like what we have seen, we would not have joined the GoDaddy family. They have overhauled their leadership team and attracted tech talent from the best-of-the-best. We love “the new GoDaddy” that CEO Blake Irving and his team have created, especially their new approach with advertising, product focus and UX.</p>

  <p>Though neither GoDaddy’s brand nor operations are being integrated into ours, we are excited to be a positive influence on them with how to make even more improvements to better serve the Web pro community.</p>

  <h4 id="will-media-temple-be-merging-with-godaddy">Will Media Temple be merging with GoDaddy?</h4>
  <p>No, we keep operating independently. The strategy to keep the two companies operating independently was critical for us. While we are excited about GoDaddy CEO Blake Irving’s vision to build bridges between GoDaddy and the Web developer community, the commitment to maintain (mt)’s independent operations is what sealed the deal for us.</p>

  <h4 id="how-does-this-affect-me-as-an-mt-customer">How does this affect me, as an (mt) customer?</h4>
  <p>It doesn’t. (mt) and GoDaddy continue to operate independently, so it’s ‘business as usual.’ We’ll keep doing what we do best: serving you and helping you succeed online.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Me believing any of these answers is predicated by me “trusting” the author; my web-host. While I have implicitly trusted the intentions of Media Temple over the years I have used their service, I have absolutely no trust for Go Daddy. And the reason is simple: They have shown time and again to have no integrity.</p>

<p>Integrity is a key element in your relationship with your web-host, as you are giving them a lot of trust in the execution and support of your personal and business ventures. Sebastiaan de With has summarized perfectly how GoDaddy has shown they don’t have the type of integrity I’m interested in my host having:</p>

<div>
	<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>“<a href="https://twitter.com/Scobleizer">@Scobleizer</a>: <a href="https://twitter.com/sdw">@sdw</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mediatemple">@mediatemple</a> why switch? What are you looking for that you don&#39;t currently have?”&#10;&#10;Integrity. <a href="http://t.co/DEL6nu9rK8">pic.twitter.com/DEL6nu9rK8</a></p>&mdash; Sebastiaan de With (@sdw) <a href="https://twitter.com/sdw/statuses/390172367856496640">October 15, 2013</a></blockquote>
	<script async="" src="http://panke.me//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div>

<p>And so, with that, I must choose to vote with the only voice I have: my business. Which means I’m looking at the alternative hosts for the first time in many years. I currently run “unmanaged” VPS-style hosting via a DV-Developer at Media Temple, so my interests are specifically in finding a competitive and well-respected alternative in that space. If you are a Grid-Service or DV-Managed user; this list may not be useful for you.</p>

<p>For my analysis, I’m explicitly targeting the “$50/month” price point in unmanaged servers (tier 2 at MT). Let’s enumerate what I get at Media Temple for that price:</p>

<ul>
  <li>16 cores; un-documented “fast-enough” CPU speeds.</li>
  <li>2 GB of memory.</li>
  <li>40 GB of RAID-10 storage.</li>
  <li>650 GB bandwidth.</li>
  <li>Root + SSH access.</li>
  <li>Old but current-enough OpenVZ kernel capable of running Ubuntu 13.04.</li>
  <li>Parallels power panel</li>
  <li>Good top-level tools for re-provisioning, restoring in emergencies, upgrading on-the-spot, and managing DNS.</li>
  <li>Basic real-time server statistics</li>
  <li>Good tech support</li>
  <li>No built-in backups.</li>
</ul>

<p>Now, let’s look at some competition (in no particular order)!</p>

<table class="table table-bordered">
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Host</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Price</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">CPU</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Memory</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Disk</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Bandwidth</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Other Details</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Thoughts</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.atum.com/vps-hosting/unmanaged-vps/">ATUM</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$49 (Bronze)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1@2.9Ghz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">50GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2TB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">10K RPM Drives,Raid 5.</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Not a fan of the single core, and their docs on their VM tech and kernel level is absent. Have to contact for OS details.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.linode.com">Linode</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$40 (2GB)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">8@2x priority</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">96GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">4TB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Xen,HA,Data Center Choices,<a href="https://www.linode.com/linodes/">Image Config Tools</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Linode looks very powerful, and I like their backup pricing and very configurable tools. Xen hypervisor is very nice. 8 cores is good.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/pricing">Digital Ocean</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$40 (Tier 4)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2@2-3Ghz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">4GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">60GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">4TB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">SSD,KVM,2-factor,custom admin,multiple data centers</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Only complaint on specs is cores. Price is good. Popular with the “hip” crowd. Custom admin looks nice. No documentation on kernel/OS options on site without registering. Competitive snapshots and backups for pricing. <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community">Awesome community docs</a>.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://rimuhosting.com/">RimuHosting</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$50 (slider configurable)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2@?</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2.5GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">48GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">100GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Xen,Market pricing,slider config,multi data center,dated 12.04 Ubuntu only.</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">I tried RimuHosting previously. It’s a good company and they have decent tools, but their core count is low, and their pricing isn’t super competitive. Also, their Ubuntu options are old.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.rackspace.com/cloud/servers/">Rackspace</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$43.80 (Tier 2)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1 “vCPU”</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">40GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">.12c/GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">…</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">I’m not particularly a fan of the EC2-ish-ness of the RackSpace offering for my personal hosting. It’s an OpenStack platform, so it’s in many ways just like EC2. Probably good for horizontal scaling, but not really right for me.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.rocketvps.com/features.html">RocketVPS</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$44.99 (RS 4)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">6@2Ghz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">75GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">3.5TB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">OpenVZ,SolusVM admin,Raid 10,<a href="http://www.rocketvps.com/features.html">full server specs</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">The pricing is competitive on RocketVPS, and I like full specs. Not a huge fan of OpenVZ, and SolusVM admin looks “just ok”. Appears to be 6 quite fast cores.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.burst.net/linvps.php">BurstNet</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$49.95 (VPS 6)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1@4Ghz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">4GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">250GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">4TB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">RAID,1 IP,OpenVZ,vePortal,6 data centers</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">A very highly rated host, but also very enterprise scale which may make impersonal. They are very competitive on price and scale. Only complaint is CPU, and that may just be bad docs. OS choices are pretty geriatric, unfortunately.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://asmallorange.com/hosting/cloud/">A Small Orange</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$50 (Tier 4)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2@2.5Ghz</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">40GB</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1TB</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">cPanel,Free Backups,KVM,Ubuntu 12.04 max,SSD,2 Dedicated IP</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Interesting mom-and-pop style. The extra IP address is nice, as is free backups, and SSD. 2 cores is a little light, and bandwidth and disk are a little lower than some others.</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Here are options I explicitly excluded for one reason or another:</p>

<ul>
  <li>EC2 and GCE - Biggest issue here is the commodity disks and the weird ephemeral IP nonsense. I’ve done a lot of hosting with EC2 through my previous life, and have no interest in bringing that into my personal world.</li>
  <li>Heroku - I’m actually a big fan of Heroku, but only if I had a desire to scale out, which I don’t. I’d rather have one efficient-as-possible VPS, as opposed to the Heroku sandbox. I also need root access.</li>
  <li>HostGator - Hello 1998. No thank you.</li>
  <li>SoftLayer - SoftLayer has a lot of good enterprise-level hosting offerings (and their dedicated is way cheaper than cloud in many cases), but it’s just not priced well for where I’m coming in. Feels targeted to bigger fish than I.</li>
  <li>DreamHost - I had nothing but bad experiences with the snarky, always ironic DreamHost “support”. I have no interest to go back and feel like I’m in a hipster coffee shop all day.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>

<p>Right now I’m exploring hosts in this option:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Digital Ocean - This looks really compelling at the moment. Pricing is great; tools look great, and they have a good reputation right now.</li>
  <li>Linode - Some folks simply swear by Linode, and I like some of their features such as HA proxy options. Pricing is good.</li>
  <li>A Small Orange - These folks have a lot of street cred, and while their pricing isn’t totally competitive everywhere, their deployment looks pretty sharp all told.</li>
</ol>

<p>So did I miss anybody you’d suggest?</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>DV Developer Acquired</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2013/10/01/dv-developer-install.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2013-10-01T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2013/10/01/dv-developer-install.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>As I discussed earlier this year, , improving their underlying virtualization software, getting a more recent kernel, and otherwise polishing up the various bits. After slogging through the last couple months of my second child being born, I finally got my head above water and pulled the trigger on migrating to a new installation. I was on an old (ve), so I chose to go to a <a href="http://mediatemple.net/webhosting/vps/developer/">DV Developer</a>, Level 2.</p>

<p>Since both the (ve) and the DV Developer are a raw, bare-bones Linux installation, there isn’t a ton to report in terms of pretty oohs and ahhs, and the provisioning and migration occurred entirely without incident (as it should be), so I can’t prattle on about that arduous process, since it was pretty much a single button press followed by “ssh #######” 5 minutes later.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I can show a few interesting tidbits for those that are interested.</p>

<h2 id="as-advertised-boxi-ness">As Advertised Boxi-ness</h2>

<p>The Level 2 is “2GB Memory, 40GB Storage, and 650GB Bandwidth”. One thing I’ve always appreciated about Media Temple is the number of cores they allow you to run on for your slice of the computing pie:</p>

<div class="imgblock">
<div class="noalignouter">
	<div class="noaligninner">

<div class="img thumbnail alignnone">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/misc/dv_stats.png" />
	
</div>

</div>
</div>
<div class="clearfix"></div>
</div>

<p>Other VPS offerings in the world seem to generally offer more like 2 or 4 cores, as opposed to the 16 made available on Media Temple. Even if the aggregate compute power available through MT is no better than other hosts, I prefer it being split across cores like this when hosting concurrent web apps.</p>

<p>You can also see that I do in fact have 2GB of memory at my fingertips; no trickery there. I should also note that the disks are SAS, and the ethernet is gigabit - so you have very few bottlenecks baked in (as you might with something like EC2).</p>

<h2 id="newer-kernel-newer-virtualization-platform">Newer Kernel; Newer Virtualization Platform</h2>

<p>I lamented rather furiously about the state of the kernel on my (ve) - it was a rather ancient <code>2.6.18</code> build for OpenVZ from Parallels. Their new platform is a more recent, but not what I’d consider super modern <code>2.6.32</code>. It’s certainly new-enough for most needs. The new virtualization platform is also supposed to be more readily upgradable on their part, so hopefully it won’t fall behind quite so badly.</p>

<p>Concretely speaking, I’m currently able to run Ubuntu Server 13.04 without issue, which is a significant step forward from the 10.04 dead-end I previously encountered.</p>

<p>Media Temple also promises significant performance increases for the same resource utilization:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>DV Developer, formerly known as (ve), streamlines the DV platform for speed, performance and efficiency. Packed with the same upgrades as DV Managed – 25% increase in LAMP performance, 10X increases in backups and maintenance, and industry leading software packages including Ubuntu, CentOS, Fedora, and Debian – DV Developer also provides rebootless updates - upgrade kernel and reboot without downtime, improved stats using vSwap, and unlimited scalability by removing the previous 20 service limit per account. DV Developer customers will also benefit from the new (mt) Media Temple 20/20 Uptime Guarantee. Pricing for DV Developer, including all upgrades, remains the same starting at $30 per month with no commitments required.</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="consoles-admins-apis-etc">Consoles, Admins, APIs, Etc.</h2>

<p>None of this is particularly new (in fact, it’s effectively identical to the (ve)), but there are a number of good administrative features available:</p>

<h3 id="admin-and-stats-panel">Admin and Stats Panel</h3>

<p>MediaTemple has an a bevy of administration GUIs, and also has a stats panel that shows sliding history of box performance:</p>

<div class="imgblock">
<div class="noalignouter">
	<div class="noaligninner">

<div class="img thumbnail alignnone">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/misc/dv_admin_gui.png" />
	
</div>

</div>
</div>
<div class="clearfix"></div>
</div>

<h3 id="power-panel">Power Panel</h3>

<p>You also get a Plesk Parallels Power Panel (Pay Phat Pive Pimes Past), which allows you to perform a number of tasks from a GUI console instead of SSH-ing in:</p>

<div class="imgblock">
<div class="noalignouter">
	<div class="noaligninner">

<div class="img thumbnail alignnone">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/misc/dv_power_panel.png" />
	
</div>

</div>
</div>
<div class="clearfix"></div>
</div>

<h3 id="apis">APIs</h3>

<p>If you have need to automate your backends, you can with the <a href="http://mediatemple.net/api/">Media Temple ProDev API</a>. This allows you to do many of the things you’d expect:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Add services (instances)</li>
  <li>Get current service information</li>
  <li>Reboot services</li>
  <li>Get service statistics, warnings, thresholds</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>

<p>Overall I’m quite happy with the new DV Developer. It’s a much needed upgrade, and it has allowed me to modernize my stack across the board without having to work around any particular issues. While performance seems quite good, I had never really felt any reason to complain there, so I can’t speak about the marketed improvements; yet it wouldn’t surprise me given the advancements made (even just in kernels alone).</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Notice: Site Update</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2012/11/02/site-updates.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2012-11-02T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2012/11/02/site-updates.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>I just did a pretty big refresh of my site on the backend. The only change that should impact folks directly is that the feed URLs changed:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code>/feed</code> is now <code>/atom.xml</code></li>
  <li><code>/category/[...]/feed</code> is now <code>/category/[...]/atom.xml</code></li>
  <li><code>/tag/[...]/feed</code> is now <code>/tag/[...]/atom.xml</code></li>
</ul>

<p>I’ve put in some 301s for those URLs, so hopefully feeds will automatically update for you.</p>

<p>If you have any issues with the site (links that don’t work, etc) please <a href="http://panke.me/contact.html">let me know</a>!</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>3 Weeks with CloudFlare</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2011/08/29/3-weeks-with-cloudflare.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2011-08-29T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2011/08/29/3-weeks-with-cloudflare.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     
<div class="img thumbnail pull-right">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/cloudflare.png" />
	
</div>

<p>A few weeks ago I posted that I . I received a good bit of feedback on the post, so I thought it would be good to do a follow-up that covers the things I’ve learned and my overall impression since I first enabled this service.</p>

<div class="imgblock">
<div class="noalignouter">
	<div class="noaligninner">

<div class="img thumbnail alignnone">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/views.png" />
	
</div>

</div>
</div>
<div class="clearfix"></div>
</div>

<p>The first thing I will note is that I have had no technical issues with the service as of yet. It has run flawlessly since I turned it on and started tinkering. As you can see from the above graph, a steady flow of traffic has been sent through their system for my site, and I’ve had no complaints or known issues over the past several days. So far so good on that front.</p>

<p>I received some skepticism about the performance of CloudFlare from folks on Twitter, and although I admittedly didn’t share any particular specs regarding the performance, it was clear from the seat of my pants that everything was faster. I decided to go ahead and do some analysis with a dumped cache, Firebug, and some hosts file editing so I could bypass CloudFlare.</p>

<p>Here is a snippet of the network downloads of my site running directly against my WordPress install:</p>

<div class="imgblock">
<div class="noalignouter">
	<div class="noaligninner">

<div class="img thumbnail alignnone">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/my_server_timeline.png" />
	
		<div class="well well-small">From my Server</div>
	
</div>

</div>
</div>
<div class="clearfix"></div>
</div>

<p>Here is a similar snapshot as pulled from CloudFlare:</p>

<div class="imgblock">
<div class="noalignouter">
	<div class="noaligninner">

<div class="img thumbnail alignnone">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/cloudflare_timeline.png" />
	
		<div class="well well-small">From CloudFlare</div>
	
</div>

</div>
</div>
<div class="clearfix"></div>
</div>

<p>As you can see - the latency from the CloudFlare servers is perceptibly better. Also note that while there is a built-in “wait” against my site (the purple section), there is effectively no wait from CloudFlare. Feel free to try this yourself against www.realjenius.com using the IP addresses above, if you’d like.</p>

<p>Now, to be completely fair, this isn’t entirely apples to apples. One of the CloudFlare features I didn’t tout when I did the initial write-up that I have since enabled is the automatic minification of resources. CloudFlare can automatically minify Javascript, CSS, and HTML in your site markup, and cache the result. This is even part of the free service. While I use some minified resources already, my basic site markup is not compressed (nor is the generated HTML markup for my posts), so there is definitely some benefit to be gained here.</p>

<div class="img thumbnail pull-right">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/minify.png" />
	
</div>

<p>When connected to my server directly, without a cache, the initial download was <strong>417.4 KB</strong>. When connected through CloudFlare, the initial download was <strong>293.4 KB</strong>. That’s a pretty significant difference.</p>

<p>One other interesting metric: over the past month CloudFlare has delivered hundreds of MB of cached resources on my behalf; effectively free bandwidth for me. Here is a bandwidth graph for my server over the past three months from within the MediaTemple monitoring tools - as you can see, there is a clear reduction (and stabilization) of the bandwidth consumption once August hits.</p>

<div class="imgblock">
<div class="noalignouter">
	<div class="noaligninner">

<div class="img thumbnail alignnone">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/bandwidth.png" />
	
</div>

</div>
</div>
<div class="clearfix"></div>
</div>

<p>Overall, after the better part of a month, my opinion of CloudFlare is still a very favorable one. I haven’t made the jump to paid service as of yet, but am considering it much more strongly as the days progress.</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>CloudFlare and Media Temple: Free Goodies</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2011/08/09/cloudflare-and-mediatemple.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2011-08-09T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2011/08/09/cloudflare-and-mediatemple.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     
<div class="img thumbnail pull-right">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/cloudflare.png" />
	
</div>

<p>Today, <a href="http://www.mediatemple.net">Media Temple</a> <a href="http://weblog.mediatemple.net/2011/08/08/supercharge-your-mt-website-with-cloudflare/">announced a partnership with CloudFlare</a>, a content delivery network and security layer for websites. This is an interesting partnership for a number of reasons:</p>

<ul>
  <li>CloudFlare performs content caching and delivery. This means that static content will be distributed regionally, and from (ideally) faster and more redundant hardware than your own. CDN distribution is almost always a good thing.</li>
  <li>Additionally, CloudFlare shields your system from many malicious attacks, and also monitors for malicious activity (think botnets, spam, email scraping, etc).</li>
  <li>The CloudFlare integration is, generally speaking, completely transparent. This is possible because CloudFlare is actually a site proxy. Unlike many CDN platforms, where you must route static content to some staticcdn.url.somewhere, CloudFlare is the top-level destination for your DNS, and then internally routes traffic from their system to yours, anywhere it need be dynamic.</li>
  <li>For your first personal site, CloudFlare is free!</li>
</ul>

<p>As of early yesterday morning (just after it was announced), RealJenius.com has been running on CloudFlare. Over time, most of the traffic has migrated; since it relies entirely on DNS propagation, it takes a little time. I experienced a blip with my local router’s DNS cache that temporarily made my site in-accessible, but that had nothing to do with the process, and aside from that it has “just worked”. It took me no more time than it takes to brew a single Keurig cup of coffee.</p>

<p>This site runs on a Media Temple (ve) with Nginx, and I had to perform no manual intervention. I clicked through the wizard to set up my site, and despite hosting several sites on my VPS, Media Temple suggested options, and choosing the correct domain re-wired the correct ANames, and everything has seemed to run along perfectly fine.</p>

<div class="img thumbnail pull-left">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/cloudflare/it-starts.png" />
	
		<div class="well well-small">The Traffic Starts!</div>
	
</div>

<p>Since then, I’ve logged in to CloudFlare, and I’m just starting to see pretty graphs of traffic. The lines indicate different information:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Green indicates valid requests.</li>
  <li>Purple indicates requests from addresses flagged as spam generators.</li>
  <li>Red indicates threat traffic: bots and other malicious requests looking for vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>

<p>CloudFlare also shows bandwidth and traffic savings, and as it stands now, nearly 40% of the traffic to my site has been reduced thanks to the service, and multiple MB of bandwidth. This is prior to full DNS propagation, so I only expect it to increase. Other stats are available about how often search engines have scanned your site, unique visitor counts, and a bevy of information about visitor locality. A lot of the information provides a good corollary to Google Analytics (another service that is surprisingly free).</p>

<p>Up to this point, my description of the service has probably made you think “what’s the catch?” - admittedly, I wondered the same thing when I took the blue pill. In reality, there isn’t one, other than hooking you with free candy. CloudFlare is a tiered service. The free version, which is what is offered out of the gates to Media Temple hosted folks, is free even directly through their site; Media Temple has just seamlessly integrated the services so it’s easier to enable (which it definitely is). They also have a Pro and Enterprise tier - from which there are a number of benefits:</p>

<ul>
  <li>More control over threat level management - The free version runs with a default threat level, of which you have limited control.</li>
  <li>Real-time traffic statistics - The reason I’m just now seeing traffic stats for my site is simply that they are delayed 24 hours on the free version.</li>
  <li>Better caching - The pro mode promises “faster subsequent page loads” via the use of prioritized/optimized caching (most important resources) and a smart pre-fetching system.</li>
  <li>Other features can be found on their <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/plans.html">Pricing &amp; Features</a> page.</li>
</ul>

<p>CloudFlare’s pro plan is currently $20 a month for the first site, and $5 a month for each additional site. Overall, two thumbs up from me regarding ease-of-installation, price, and (at least so far) performance. I’ll probably report back when I’ve had more time under this new umbrella.</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Theme Change</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2011/07/29/theme-change.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2011-07-29T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2011/07/29/theme-change.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>I just ripped the majority of the guts out of the my site’s theme because it was just way too fancy for my tastes. The new theme is light, fluffy, and has fewer calories.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>RealJenius.com - Now With Less PHP</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2011/04/12/realjenius-on-play.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2011-04-12T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2011/04/12/realjenius-on-play.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>I have long time been a proponent of WordPress for a quick and painless blogging platform. For years I toiled to create 
a favorable personal blogging platform; re-inventing it time and again in some variant of Java technologies, and constantly being fed up. Despite being a good learning experience, my custom blog was always a thorough pain in my ass to maintain.
That’s what made Drupal, and later WordPress, so appealing. I was able to focus on what I wanted to do, which was deliver    content, without having to futz with my rushed and unfinished web forms. I knew that my site software was going to be
maintained and regularly audited by community reports with respect to security, etc. Unfortunately, despite the flexibility
and plugin architecture, WordPress carries a certain degree of cruft with it:</p>

<ul>
  <li>PHP is surprisingly hard to host scalably and efficiently.</li>
  <li>WordPress needs a rack of plugins installed to be even remotely performant - most of it gross caching schemes.</li>
  <li>I rather despise maintaining relational database installations.</li>
</ul>

<p>I’ve never been a fan of PHP in any shape or form, so I think it says a lot about how burnt out I had become on trying to 
build a one-man CMS, that I was using WP, and singing its praises.</p>

<p>A post over at <a href="http://nesbot.com">Nesbot.com</a> inspired me to revisit my embargo on personal blog coding, as Brian Nesbitt <a href="http://nesbot.com/2011/11/22/now-running-on-play-2-beta">detailed how he migrated his blog 
with Play 2.0</a>. What struck me in particular was, not so much that he was using <a href="http://www.playframework.org">Play!</a>,
nor that he was now using the shiny 2.0 beta, but that he had built his site without any complex data-store on the back-end.</p>

<p>Suddenly: lightbulb! This triggered me to explore the ideas he so graciously shared with his public site code on github:
<a href="https://github.com/briannesbitt/nesbot.com">https://github.com/briannesbitt/nesbot.com</a>. Of particular note:</p>

<ul>
  <li>His blog entries are simply Play! UI templates.</li>
  <li>The entire blog-entry history is loaded in memory at startup, and cross-indexed for the various navigation.</li>
  <li>The comment system is provided by <a href="http://www.disqus.com">Disqus</a>.</li>
  <li>Blog entries are committed to GitHub, and ostensibly pulled to his server where he then simply restarts the 
server to load the new article.</li>
</ul>

<p>I didn’t spend much time actually digesting his code, but I appreciate that he posted his approach online, as it
immediately got my gears turning. While I’m not quite ready to share the source of my site (more on this in a moment),
I will share some details on the approach I’ve taken:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Each of my blog posts is a template file, and has a “meta” comment on the top. This defines things like the
title, a short summary, the publish date, tags (comma-separated), the category (journal or article),
and optionally some additional compatibility bits, like a legacy id (see below). The comment is YAML formatted
so I have some leniency as I’m authoring, and good error reporting if I get the formatting wrong.</li>
  <li>The file name represents the blog “slug”.</li>
  <li>On startup, I spin through the entire post directory recursively, reading the header comments one-by-one, and
tossing them into a series of in-memory indexes for traversal. The collections are sorted in date descending order,
as that’s the most generally useful ordering for the site.</li>
  <li>The re-load process can also be triggered by an administrative call through the HTTP interface. The reload is completely free of locks via some judicious use of atomic references.</li>
  <li>I’m also using <a href="http://www.disqus.com">Disqus</a> for my comment system, like Brian. Importing from my
existing wordpress site was, for the most part painless. I simply installed the Disqus plugin into my WP install,
and did an export. The hardest part was supporting legacy identifiers. Turns out the IDs that
it uses are: <code>[wpid] http://[site-address]?p=[wpid]</code> - this is where the legacy ID entry comes in to play above.</li>
  <li>I have a private git repo on my server, and every time I write an article, I simply push to the git repo. The server then pulls from the git repo, and I run the administrative reload.</li>
  <li>I’m using <a href="http://alexgorbatchev.com/SyntaxHighlighter/">SyntaxHighlighter</a> for code highlighting. The highlighters that are declared in the post are loaded in “on-demand”, so the included JS is kept to a minimum.</li>
  <li>I have a few custom Play! tags to make writing blogs easier - they do things like reverse routes to other blog posts into anchor tags, create captioned image markup, and dynamically generate series blocks (as seen in my <a href="http://panke.me/tags/distilling-jruby">Distilling JRuby</a> series).</li>
  <li>I’m using a Play profile ID on my server, and %prod. prefixes to support dev and prod properties concurrently
in the same file.</li>
  <li>I’m using a variant of <a href="http://www.playframework.org/community/snippets/17">This Ubuntu up-start script</a> to bootstrap my Play! Framework runtime.</li>
  <li>Thanks to the expressiveness of the the Play routes system, I was able to effectively model my URLs without any
change in pathing to match the existing WordPress site. There are some exceptions, but they are only places where I
felt a change was for the best.</li>
</ul>

<p>I have immediately noticed a complete lack of latency on page loads, which I find quite refreshing. Occasionally one of the Javascript chunks blocks the page-load a bit (whether it be Google Analytics, Disqus, the syntax highlighter, or the Twitter widget, I can’t say). I am keeping my eye out for this, and hopefully will figure it out with Firebug, and I can squash it. Overall, this has been a minimalist’s dream as compared to something chunky like WP.</p>

<p>Before I globally share the blog code, I really wanted to get a few things tidied up (call me vain):</p>

<ul>
  <li>Right now the administrative reload is a bit of a shim. I’d really like this to be an automated “on-git-update” event, 
so my involvement is simply a matter of avoiding malformed posting, and pushing the content.</li>
  <li>My error handling is pretty weak-sauce right now - I was slapping this together pretty quickly; the majority of my 
time was in converting my blog entries (which I did by hand, like an idiot).</li>
  <li>Right now I’m using Play 1.2.4 - I want to move to 2.0, but unlike Brian, I plan to wait until it’s final before 
converting.</li>
</ul>

<p>Once I get through those hurdles, I’ll throw out a follow-up, and hopefully some public mirrors so folks can get some
value (however small) out of my derivative journey. If you have any questions in the mean-time, <a href="http://panke.me/contact">send me a note</a>.</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Site Analytics</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2009/09/16/site-analytics.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2009-09-16T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2009/09/16/site-analytics.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     
<div class="img thumbnail pull-right">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/site-analytics/statistics.png" />
	
</div>

<p>With this site refresh, I decided I was going to do something that, for the most part, I avoided on my last site incarnation. I’ve installed a battery of statistical gathering tools on my site to see how users are using the various globs of data. It has become eye-opening to me just how much data you actually can gather now-a-days. Some of the tools I have configured on Realjenius.com:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://google.com/analytics">Google Analytics</a> - Thorough statistics regarding site usage and benchmarking against public sites Tracks nationality, IP, user agents, click-throughs, and more.</li>
  <li><a href="http://feedburner.com">FeedBurner</a> - Tracks the usage of your site’s RSS feeds, and click-throughs on those feeds.</li>
  <li><a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/stats/">Wordpress-Stats</a> - Tracks statistics centric to your wordpress installation. This is particularly valuable for seeing the content on the site in relation to each other (which particular articles are more popular).</li>
  <li><a href="http://bit.ly/">Bit.Ly</a> - Shortened URLs for social sites that track received clicks. One of the things I’ve started to like about this is the track-backs it provides to the actual conversations that mention the link.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.google.com/webmasters/index2.html">Google Webmaster Tools</a> - Tracks search rankings for your site. Probably the most narrow-focused of the tools on this list, but the only one that actually gives insight into the actual GoogleBot indexing process.</li>
</ul>

<p>What’s fascinating about all of this is that none of these tools provide a complete picture. Admittedly, Google Analytics gets the closest, however it’s information is high-level enough that the aggregation can hide some fascinating details. Great for overall statistics, however.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, tools like Bit.Ly and FeedBurner let you see the usage of and navigation to your content outside the normal purview of your site.</p>

<p>Overall, the point is that the value of a particular statistic is all about perspective. Different tools see different things, so it’s all about the slice of metrics you’re looking at, and how you are looking at it.</p>

<p>Additionally, as part of the rewrite, I did finally decided to invest in configuring sitemap tools so that Realjenius.com <a href="http://www.realjenius.com/sitemap.xml">would have a sitemap.xml</a>. It’s been interesting to see the influence it had on how Google in particular indexed my site - not sure if it’s made a positive difference yet or not - I don’t have enough new unique content under the sitemap to be sure.</p>

<p>Time will certainly tell.</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Welcome to the new RealJenius.com</title>
  <link>http://panke.me/journal/2009/09/08/welcome-to-the-new-realjenius-com.html</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2009-09-08T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://panke.me/journal/2009/09/08/welcome-to-the-new-realjenius-com.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     
<div class="img thumbnail pull-right">
	<img src="http://panke.me/images/articles/misc/HomeAlone.jpg" />
	
</div>

<p>Oh no! Change!</p>

<p>That’s right, kiddies. I’ve uprooted all that was Realjenius.com once again. This new version includes a major UI refresh (obviously), as well as a significant shift on the underlying platform.</p>

<p>I intentionally avoided migrating content this time through - I’m ready for a fresh start, and eventually I’d like to drop archive.realjenius.com like a bad habit. For now, I’ll be tracking Google Analytics to help make that decision; for better or worse some of the stuff floating around over there is still rather popular in google searches.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more on what I changed, why I changed it, and how I’m liking the new changes. Oh, and if you have no idea who I am or what I’m talking about, be sure to read my <a href="http://panke.me/about.html">about page</a>.</p>

  ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>